[Episode 902]
The One Where Emma Cries
Version: 1.0 (2002.10.16)
You said you'd marry Joey?
조이와 결혼을 하겠다고 얘기했단 말이야?
Okay you have to realize,
I was exhausted, I was emotional,
상황을 생각하봐, 난 피곤했고 감정적이고..
I would have said yes to anybody.
누가 청혼을 해도 승낙했을 꺼라고
Like that time you and I got married!
우리 둘이 결혼했을 때 처럼 말이야
I'm not helping.
도움이 안되는 말이네
So you said yes to him,
그러니까 방금 조이의 청혼을 받아들이고,
and you just had our baby?
우리의 아기를 가졌단 말이지?
That is right and traditionally
바로 그거야,
그리고 원래는 아기의 아빠가 산모한테 선물을 줘야하는데
The daddy is supposed to
give the mummy a present.
But I am prepared to let that go.
난 그걸 포기할 의사가 있어
So when I came in here to see if
you wanted to maybe start things up again,
그러니까 내가 다시 사귈 생각 없냐고 물어보러 왔을때 넌..
you were engaged to my best friend.
내 가장 친한 친구와 약혼 한 사이였다는 거지?
Well?Really?
진짜?
I thought Chandler was your best friend.
챈들러가 가장 친한 친구인 줄 알았는데?
Well, Chandler's my oldest friend,
but Joey's my? No! Ah!
챈들러는 가장 오래 사귄 친구지, 조이는..
안돼, 이러지마!
Ooooo!
Hey you guys I'm gonna take off.
얘들아 나 이제 갈꺼야, 가기 전에 인사 할라고..
I just wanted to let you guys know,
say goodbye..
Rachel said she'd marry you?!
레이첼이 너랑 결혼 하겠다고 했단 말이야?
This isn't the right room, sorry folks.
내가 방을 잘못 들어왔네, 죄송합니다
F*R*I*E*N*D*S
902: The One Where Emma Cries
버전: 0.8 (2002.10.4)
Written by: Dana Klein Borkow
South Park Korean Translation Team
E- mail: spkor@hotmail.com
WWW: http://www.spkor.com
번역: KidFromKor / 싱크: Sanger
싱크조절: 변정주
Transcribed by: Eric Aasen
Sinked by: Baskin
E-mail: baskin7x@hotmail.com
["It's a Boy!"]
'아들 축하합니다'
부정적인 태도는 보이기 싫으니까
Ok, I don't wanna be negative
니가 산 '대부분'의 사인은 괜찮다고 얘기하지
so I'll say that
most of the signs you bought are good.
'딸 축하합니다' 사인이 다 팔렸더라고
No they ran out of "It's a girl"
그래도 이건 고칠 수 있어
but I can fix this one,
'아들이 아닌것 축하합니다'
봐, 괜찮지?
See?
너무나 섹시한걸
So sexy.
자기야?
Honey.
응
Yea yea.
Honey why don't you go lie down.
가서 좀 누워있지 그래?
아니야, 로스랑 레이첼이 금방 올텐데 뭐
No, no, Ross and Rachel will be back soon
and then I gotta go to the office
그리고 사무실에도 가봐야돼
내가 풍선을 만들어 내고 있는건가?
Am I producing them?
왜 이리 피곤한거야?
Why're you so tired?
어제 잠이 안오더라고
Couldn't sleep last night you know,
게다가 오늘 있을 미팅이 걱정이 되는데
Then I started worrying about this
big divisional meeting that I have later today,
걱정을 할수록 잠이 안오는거야
the more I worried about it
the more I couldn't sleep..
이런 생각이 들었지, '지금 자면 6시간 잘 수 있겠군'
Y'know? I was like,
if I fall asleep now
I'll get six hours sleep,
But if I fall asleep now
또, '지금 자면 5시간 잘 수 있겠군'
I'll get five hours sleep.
아무리 애를 써도 잠이 안오더라고
Not matter what I did I couldn't fall asleep.
이렇게 했으면 됬을텐데
You know what you should've done,
방금 그 이야기를 자신한테 하면 바로 잘 수 있었을텐데 말이야
You should have told yourself that little story.
-안녕
-Hi
-Hi, welcome home!
사인은 피비가 준비한거야
Phoebe did the signs!
얘들아, 너무 고마워
Oh you guys thanks for doing this.
사람들이 보내온 이 선물들 좀 봐
Look at all the stuff people sent!
Oh Ah!
오 마이 갓, 이거야 말로 모든 엄마들에게 필요한거지
Oh my gosh
there's something every mother needs,
아파트 전체를 차지하는 거대한 고릴라 인형 말이야
A giant stuffed gorilla
that takes up the entire apartment!
대체 사람들은 무슨 생각을 하고 이런 선물을...
What are people think…
오 얘들아, 너무 마음에 들어
Oh you guys I love it.
로스는 어디있어?
Hey so where's Ross?
아래층에서 택시에 있는 짐을 내려놓고 있어
He's downstairs getting
the rest of the stuff out of the cab.
아직도 우리한테 화가 나 있어?
Is he still mad at us?
나보다는 너한테 화가 났지
Well, you more then me,
나한테는 그래 오래동안 화를 못내지,
but he can't stay to mad at me.
I mean, I just had his baby.
내가 방금 걔 아기를 낳았거든
That's not fair! I can't do that.
이거 불공평하잖아, 난 그런거 못하는데
로스가 올라올 때 니가 여기 없는게 낫을지도 몰라
Yeah, I'm not so sure
you should be here when he comes up.
내가 이럴 줄 알았어, 나도 여기 있지 않을려고 했는데
See this is what I was afraid of,
I didn't think I should be here either
But somebody said he'd be over it by now.
누군가가 벌써 화를 풀었을꺼라고 하더라고
내가 뭘 알겠어? 난 더 큰 고릴라를 사자고 했잖아
Hey, what do I know?
I wanted to get a bigger gorilla.
[A Boardroom]
시카고, 뉴욕, 런던의 자료는 일괄적으로 충실한 편이에요
The numbers we are seeing Chicago,
New York and London
are consistently solid,
하지만 여러 지점에서는 실망스러운 결과를 보였어요
but many of our officers have reported disappointing fields.
보스턴, 아틀란타, 휴스턴을 비롯한 수많은 지점이 모두 떨어졌지만
Boston is down,
Atlanta is down, Houston is down,
I could go on and on
but instead of boring you
모두 얘기하지 않고 바로 내 42포인트 계획으로 들어가죠
I'll go straight to my 42 point plan.
월터
Walter.
너무나 귀여워
She's just so cute!
그냥 아기의 귀를 물어 뜯어서 맨날 빨아먹고 싶어
I just wanna bite her ear off
and use it and a sucking candy.
Phoebe!
피비..
그래도 저 귀여운 발은 가져다 버킷에다 넣고 싶은걸
But I could take one of those little feet
and put it in a pita pocket.
대부분의 짐을 다 넣어 놨어
Okay I put most of the stuff away.
좋아, 고무 젖꼭지는?
Oh great, the pacifiers?
어.. 찬장에 있어
In the closet.
그러면 버번천은?
The burping clogs?
리넨찬장에 있어
Linen closet.
그러면.. 기저귀는?
The diapers?
병원에 있지
In the hospital.
와 너희들은 병원도 있니? 멋진데
Wow you guys got a hospital?
Fancy!
기저귀를 병원에 놔두고 왔네,
No I left the diapers at the hospital!
가방에 조금 있기는 한데 가서 더 사올께
There's some in the bag
but I'll run out and get some more.
그래, 고마워
Alright thanks,
오 로스, 커피집에 들려서 머핀 하나만 사다 줄래?
Oh Ross could you stop by
the coffee house and get me a muffin?
그래, 어떤 종류?
Sure what kind?
음.. 어디 보자..
Umm let me think...
뭘 먹을까?
What do I want,
what d-o I w-a-n-t...
괜찮아 천천히 생각해, 중요한 결정이잖아
Please take your time,
it's an important decision.
뭐 누구랑 결혼 할건지 결정하는 것도 아닌데 말이야
Not like, say, I know!
Deciding to marry someone,
This is about a muffin.
이건 '머핀'에 대한거니까
블루베리
Blueberry.
그러면 블루베리를 사올께
Blueberry it is.
Thanks.
와, 오빠 끈질긴데?
Wow, he's really not letting this go, is he?
그래, 언제까지 저럴까?
God how long do you think that's gonna last?
모르지, '잠시 떨어져 있었을 뿐이야'는 아주 빨리 없어지던데 말이야
I dunno, well he got over the
"We were on a break" thing really quickly.
지금은 그런거 걱정할 필요도 없어
Y'know I can't even worry about that right now,
나에게 이렇게 귀여운 아기가 있으니까 말이야
Cause I got the cutie little baby,
오, 너무나 사랑해서 어쩔 줄 모르겠어
Oh I can't believe how much I love her,
같이 있어도 모자라다니까
I can't get enough of her,
지금 이 순간에도 에마가 그리워,
Like right now I miss her.
I actually miss her.
진짜 그립다고
바로 여기 있는건 알지?
You know that's… that's her.
오 마이 갓, 저렇게 자고 있는 것 봐
Oh god look at her sleeping.
너무나 사랑스러워
Oh, I love her so much!
그냥 깨울래
Oh, I think I'm gonna wake her up.
Oh no, Rach, no no.
오 레이첼, 자고 있는 아기는 절대 깨우면 안되는거야
You know you're never
supposed to wake a sleeping baby..
내가 하고 싶은데로 할꺼야, 내가 만들었는데 뭐
Well I can do whatever I want!
I made her!
이리와 아기야
Come on little girl,
안녕
Hi!
'내가 그럴줄 알았지'라고 얘기하고 싶지만,
I can say I told you so
but she's kinda doing that for me.
에마가 나대신 얘기해주는것 같네
오 미안해, 엄마가 너무 미안해, 다시 자자
Oh I'm sorry mummy's so sorry
Go back to sleep, Shh. Shhh!
Shh. Shhh! Go back to sleep
다시 자자
가슴 아프지?
Breaks your heart doesn't it
진짜 안됬네..
It really does…
우리 여기 얼마나 오래 있어야 할까?
How long do you think we have to stay?.
Ok
좋아요, 모두가 찬성이면 결정된거네요
If everyone's on board, it's settled,
챈들러
Chandler,
-챈들러
-네
-Chandler?
-Yep.
당신도 찬성인가요?
Are you on board?
네
Yes.
그러면 문제는 해결됬네요,
Then, problem solved.
챈들러가 툴사에 있는 지점장으로 가게 됬어요
Chandler will be running our office in Tulsa.
오클라호마주가 마음에 들꺼에요
You're gonna love Oklahoma.
벌써 먹여보고, 기저귀도 갈아보고, 트림도 시켜봤고..
Well, alright, we already tried
feeding her, changing her, burping her,
오 이거 한번 해봐
Oh try this one!
'과거로 돌아가서 피비의 말을 들어라'
Go back in time and listen to Phoebe!
좋아, 여기 좋은 방법이 있다
Alright here's something,
아기를 몸 가까이 안고 양옆으로 빠르게 흔들어 준다
It says to try holding the baby
close to your body
And then swing her rapidly from side to side.
Ok.
그래
됐다!
It worked!
Oh
아니야, 그냥 잠시 쉬었을 뿐이야
Oh no just stopped to throw up a little bit.
오 어떻하지? 몇시간째인데 이것이 멈추질 않아
Oh come on, what am I gonna do,
its been hours and it won't stop crying.
사람이야 레이첼, '이것'이 아니야
Umm, she Rach, not it, she.
진짜 사람인지 조금 의심이 가
Yeah, I'm not so sure.
오 마이 갓, 나도 미치겠네
Oh my god, I am losing my mind.
그래, 이건 로스와 섹스를 하면 좋을게 하나도 없다는 뜻이야!
Yeah, no kidding,
This just proves no good
can come from having sex with Ross!
[Central Perk]
건터, 블루베리 머핀 2개 싸줄래요?
Hey Gunther,
can I get a couple of blueberry muffins to go?
기저귀군요
Diapers huh?
네
Yep.
레이첼이 당신의 아기를 낳았나 보군요
So I guess Rachel had you baby?
그래요, 믿겨져요?
Yep, can you believe it?
아니요
Nope!
레이첼이 당신과 잤다는 것 자체가 믿겨지지 않아요
I still can't believe she slept
with you in the first place.
뭐라고요?
Huh?
Ooh you mean like a…
아, 그러니까...
Huh?
뭐라고요?
안녕
Hey.
로스 나한테 화가 난건 알지만, 얘기를 해봐야돼
Ross, I know you're pissed at me,
but we have to talk about this.
사실.. 안해도 돼
Ah actually we don't.
좋아, 하지만 이것만은 알아둬
Fine, fine okay.
But I gotta say technically,
I didn't even do anything wrong.
원칙적으로 난 잘못한게 없어
뭐라고?
What!
You didn't do anything wrong?!
니, 니가 아무 잘못이 없다고?
I said I didn't technically.
원칙적으로는 말이야..
Okay let's put aside that you
좋아, 먼저 니가 "우연히" 할머니의 반지를 줏고
"accidentally" picked up
my grandmothers ring and you
"accidentally" proposed to Rachel.
"우연히" 레이첼한테 청혼 한 것은 제쳐두고..
Look, can I just stop you
right there for a second?
로스 잠시 말 좀 끊을 수 있을까?
사람들이 이렇게 할때 있잖아
When people do this
무슨 뜻인지 잘 모르겠단 말이야
I don't really know what that means.
계속해봐
You were saying?
니가 레이첼에게 말을 못했다는 것도 이해를 할수 있어
And I can even understand
that you couldn't tell Rachel,
그런데 왜 나한테 말을 못했지?
but why couldn't you tell me,
응? 하루종일 시간이 있었는데 안했잖아
huh? You had all day to and you didn't.
알아, 얘기 했어야 했지
I know I should've.
"미안해"
"I'm sorry."
그렇게 쓰는게 아니야, 조이
Not using it right, Joe.
"I'm sorry."
"미안해"
나 이제 갈래
I'm gonna go.
No, come on Ross!
로스, 우린 이걸 극복해내야 한다고
Look, Ross, we have to get past this.
그거 내놔
Give me the bag.
싫어, 난 어찌 할지 모르겠다고! 벌써 미안하다고 했잖아
No, look, I don't know what else to do.
I said I'm sorry!
-조이
-나한테 소리를 질러
Joey!
You should scream at me,
아니면 욕을 하던지, 나를 쳐
or-or-or curse me, or hit me.
널 때리지 않을꺼야
I'm not gonna hit you.
왜? 기분이 좋아질꺼야, 내 기분도 좋아질꺼라고
Why not? You'll feel better!
I'll feel better,
그리고 때리고 싶은거 다 알아, 눈에 다 보이는걸
and you know you want to.
I can see it in your eyes.
아니야
No I don't.
조금은 때리고 싶지
A little bit.
아니
-No.
-Little bit.
조금은
아니야
-No!
-A little bit more.
조금 더
-Give me the bag.
-No, hit me
-그거 내놔
-싫어, 날 쳐
-싫어, 날 치라고
-Give me the bag.
-Hit me.
-조이 그거 내놔
-싫어, 날 치라고
-Joey, give me the bag.
-Hit me!
Joe I'm not kidding…
-장난하는거 아니야
-날 쳐
-Hit me, hit me.
-No.
날 쳐, 날 쳐, 날 치라고!
Hit me! Hit me!
피했잖아!
You ducked!!
미안해, 반사작용이었어!
I'm sorry! It was a reflex!
오 마이 갓, 너무나 아프다고!
Oh my god, this really hurts!!!
어쩔 수 없었어, 얼굴에 주먹이 날라오면 피할 수 밖에 없잖아, 봐
I couldn't help it!
When a fist comes at your face,
you duck!.
Look!
너 왜그래!
What is the matter with you?!?
피했어야지, 왜 안피한거야!
You were supposed to duck!!!
Why didn't you duck?
병원에 가면서 얘기하는게 어때?
Why don't we talk about this
on the way to the hospital?
좋아, 병원에 간 김에 니 반사신경도 검사해봐야 겠다
Good, good yeah,
maybe while we're there,
they can check your reflexes.
"웁스.."
"Oops."
Try feeding her again.
다시 우유 먹여봐
I already fed her.
벌써 먹여봤단 말이야
I know, that's why I said "again"!
알아, 그러니까 내가 '다시'라고 했잖아
Alright you guys,
we can't turn on each other, Okay?
얘들아, 서로 적이 되서는 안돼
That's just what she wants.
저 아기가 원하는 것이 그거란 말이야
Hey.
안녕, 모니카 잠시 밖에서 얘기 좀 하면 안될까?
Monica,
can I talk to you outside for a minute?
Oh no, you guys, just stay here,
I'm gonna go check her diaper,
아니 여기서 얘기해, 난 얘 기저귀나 갈아줘야겠어
Pheebs you wanna come?
피비 좀 도와줄래?
Oh I'm kinda part of this.
아니 난.. 얘네들이랑 할 말이 있거든
Actually Pheebs its more of
a husband and wife kinda thing
사실 피비.. 부부끼리 할 말이거든
I knew I should have married Chandler.
역시 챈들러랑 결혼했어야 하는데
Okay what's up
그래, 무슨 일이야?
Ok, Umm.
좋아, 우리가 언젠가 1년동안 파리로 이사가면 좋겠다고 한거 기억나지?
You know how we always said that
it would be fun to move to Paris for a year?
You know, you could study French cooking
and I could write
자기는 프랑스 요리를 배우고, 나는 글을 쓸 수 있고..
and we could take a picnic along the Seine
센느강가에서 피크닉을 할수도 있고,
and go wine tasting in Bordeaux?
보르도에 가서 와인을 마시고..
Oh yeah.
그럼..
Okay, you know how that people say that Tulsa
좋아, 그러면 사람들이 툴사가..
is the Paris of Oklahoma?
오클라호마주의 파리라고 부르는 것도 알지?
What? Who says that?
뭐? 누가 그런 말을 해?
People who've never ever been to Paris.
파리에 한번도 가본적이 없는 사람들
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
We're moving to Tulsa!
우리 툴사로 이사갈꺼야
Excuse me?
뭐라고?
Okay, Ms. McKenna,
she kind of works above my boss,
맥케나씨가 내 상관 위의 사람인데 말이야
She asked me to move to Tulsa
and be the president of our office there,
맥케나씨가 나보고 툴사로 가서 그 지점의 점장이 되어 달라고 했단 말이야
and I was sleeping and apparently,
said yes.
그런데 내가 자고 있었는지 알았다고 해버렸어
Tulsa, Oklahoma!
오클라호마주의 툴사라고?
The Sooner State,
'더 빠른 주'잖아!
Whatever that is.
그게 무슨 뜻인지는 모르겠지만 말야
Chandler,
I don't even wanna see the musical Oklahoma!
챈들러, 난 '오클라호마' 뮤지컬도 보고 싶지 않아!
Really? Oh What A Beautiful Morning!
Surrey With A Fringe On Top.
진짜? '오 이 아름다운 아침이여' 가 싫단 말이야?
Are you trying to tell me that
we're moving to Oklahoma,
지금 우리가 오클라호마주로 이사간다고 얘기하는거야?
or that you're gay?
당신이 게이라고 얘기하는거야?
All right, not that this matters,
but did they at least offer you a huge raise?
이건 상관없는 얘기지만, 적어도 월급을 올려주겠데?
No, no, but they are
going to lease us a Ford Focus.
아니, 하지만 우리에게 포드 포커스를 임대해주겠데
I'll get out of it.
내가 처리할께
Thank you.
그래
What is wrong with Emma?
에마 왜저래?
Oh she misunderstood,
에마가 잘못들어서 그래,
She thought she was moving to Tulsa.
자기가 툴사로 이사가는 줄 착각했나봐
[Ms. McKenna's Office]
Umm ma'am, do you have a minute?
저, 잠시 시간 좀 낼 수 있을까요?
I kind of have some bad news.
안좋은 소식이 있는데요
I don't think I can move to Tulsa.
툴사로 이사 갈수 없을 것 같아요
What?
뭐라고요?
It's a funny story, actually.
사실 듣고보면 참 웃긴 일이죠
I kind of fell asleep
in the meeting this morning
오늘 아침 미팅에서 제가.. 잠이 들었었죠
So when I said I'd move to Tulsa,
그래서 제가 툴사로 이사가겠다고 했을때,
I didn't really know what I was saying.
무슨 말을 하는지 몰랐던거죠
You fell asleep?
잠이 들었다고?
But only because I was up all night worried about this meeting,
그 미팅 걱정 때문에 밤을 새서 그런거에요
Ain't that funny?
웃기지 않아요?
Irony?
아이러니하지 않아요?
Not a fan, alright.
그런거 싫어하시나 보죠?
See, here's the thing.
문제는 이거에요
I went home
집에 가서 부인에게 툴사에 이사가는 것에 대해서 얘기를 했더니
and told my wife about Tulsa
and she won't go.
못가겠데요
See, me, I love Tulsa!
전 툴사가 좋아요
Tulsa is heaven! Tulsa is Italy?
툴사는 천국이에요, 툴사는 이탈리아와 같죠
Please don't make me go there!
제발 보내지 말아 주세요
Chandler, I…
챈들러, 난..
No no no! Look, Carol,
아니요, 캐롤..
Can I call you Carol?
캐롤이라고 불러도 되나요?
Wh-why would I when your name is Elaine?
이름이 일레인인데 제가 왜 캐롤이라고 부르겠어요?
Oh what a great picture of your son,
오, 아드님의 너무나 멋진 사진이군요
Strapping!
억세보이는군요
That's a picture of your daughter, isn't it,
따님 사진이군요
Well she's lovely.
I like a girl with a strong jaw.
너무나 사랑스럽군요, 전 강한 턱을 가진 여자가 좋거든요
I'll call you from Tulsa.
툴사에 가서 전화드리죠
[The Hospital]
Hey, so how is it?
헤이, 손은 어때?
I broke my thumb.
엄지손가락이 부러졌어
Your thumb?
엄지손가락이라고?
That's weird.
이상하군
You sure you're punching right?
Make a fist.
제대로 주먹을 쥐긴 하는거야? 주먹 쥐어봐
Maybe later.
나중에 하지 뭐
Ross I feel terrible.
로스 너무나 미안해
You know what, you can go,
I just have to fill out some forms.
이제 가봐도 돼, 이 서류만 적어내면 되니까
You, you want me to help you with that?
내.. 내가 좀 도와줄까?
Why, does it look like I'm having trouble
with my misshapen claw?
왜 이 망가진 발톱으로 글쓰는게 힘들어 보이냐?
Name?
이름?
I know Ross but what's it short for?
You know like,
로스인건 물론 알지, 하지만 뭘 줄인거야?
like Rossel
예를 들어.. '로슬'이라던가
or Rosstepher.
'로스토퍼'라던가
Just Ross!
그냥 로스야
It's pretty,
예쁘네
Okay date of birth?
좋아, 생년월일?
You know my birthday.
내 생일 알잖아
Sure,
알고 말고
May...
5.. 9월...?
tember...
October 18th.
10월 18일이야
Occupation?
직업?
Dinosaurs.
공룡
Actually I'm a palian…
사실 고생..
Dinosaurs is fine…
공룡이면 될꺼야
The drawing is not.
그렇다고 그림으로 그리는건 안되지
Alright, who,
who do you want as your emergency contact?
좋아, 긴급 연락처는 누구로 할까?
Ah, Rachel I guess.
레이첼로 하지 뭐
Okay, relationship,
좋아, 긴급 연락처와의 관계..?
Boy this could take a while.
휴, 오래 걸리겠는걸
Just ah…
just put roommate.
그냥.. 룸메이트라고 적어
Come on, you guys are more then that!
이봐, 너희들은 그 이상이잖아
I mean, you're gonna get together right?
다시 사귈꺼잖아, 안그래?
I don't think that we are.
아닌것 같아
But you two were supposed to be together.
하지만.. 너희 둘은 원래 같이 있어야 되잖아
Well, I thought so too,
나도 그렇게 생각했지
But then she said she'd marry you.
하지만 레이첼은 너와 결혼하겠다고 했어
Come on, Ross, that didn't mean anything!
이봐 로스, 그건 아무 의미도 없었잖아
She just had the baby,
레이첼은 방금 아기를 낳았었고,
She was all freaked out about doing it alone,
혼자 키운다는 것 때문에 겁에 질려있었고..
She would have said yes to anybody.
누구의 청혼이었어도 받아들였을꺼야
Yeah that's what she said.
그래, 레이첼도 같은 말을 했어
-So?
-So I don't wanna be just anybody.
-그래서?
-그래서 난 그 '아무 누구'가 되고 싶지 않단 말이야
Wow.
와
You know what, it's,
it's better this way anyway.
있잖아, 이러는게 더 낫은거야
I mean I don't know what I was thinking,
내가 무슨 생각을 한건지 모르겠어,
going down that road again with us.
다시 우리 둘의 관계를 시작하려고 했다니
It's just much easier
if we're just friends who have a kid.
그냥 아기를 같이 낳은 친구로 남는게 더 낫아
-Really?
-Yeah.
-진짜?
-응
And you're Okay with that?
그렇게 되도 괜찮아?
Yes. I mean,
it's what we always planned.
그럼, 원래 그렇게 계획을 했었잖아
And if you have a plan, you should stick to it.
그리고 계획을 한번 세우면 그걸 지켜야 하는거라고
That's why they call them plans. Hello?
그러니까 계획이라고 하는거지
I'm fine.
나 괜찮아
Hey, for what it's worth,
내 생각엔 말이야,
With Rachel, I don't think you'll ever be just
너와 레이첼의 관계에서 넌 절대 "아무 누구"가 되지 않을꺼야
"anybody."
Hey there you go!
야, 바로 그거야
"Thanks."
"고마워"
Oh my God!
How long has she been crying?
오 마이 갓, 얼마나 오래동안 우는거야?
About a week and a half.
일주일 반 정도 된거 같은데?
Well alright, looks like you guys have got it
under control so I'm just gonna go.
자, 너희들이 다 처리한것 같으니 난 이제 가볼께
No! Really?
아니야? 진짜?
Misery really does love company.
'고통은 옆에 사람과 같이 나누는게 좋다'는 말이 사실이야?
All right!
좋아!
Rach, try holding her a different way.
레이첼, 다른 방법으로 안아봐
You guys, I'm doing the best I can,
얘들아, 난 최선을 다하고 있는거란 말이야
Anyone else is welcome to try.
너희들이 한번 해보고 싶으면 해봐
Alright, I'll try, fine! Yes,
좋아 내가 한번 안아볼께
-좋아
-여기 있어
Okay! Here you go.
Shh! Nothing works with this child!
이 아기는 구제불능이야!
Oh god what am I gonna do you guys,
오 마이 갓, 나 어떻게 해야돼 얘들아!
I can't even comfort my own baby!
I'm the worst mother ever!
내 아기 울음도 멈추지 못한다니, 난 최악의 엄마인가봐
You're just new at this,
넌 아직 서툴러서 그런 것 뿐이야
It'll get better,
괜찮아 질꺼야
Think about your first day at work.
첫출근한 날을 생각해봐
I mean, that couldn't have been easy
but you figured that out.
그것도 힘들었겠지만 결국은 잘 해냈잖아
Yeah I don't think dressing provocatively
is going to help me here!
내가 지금 옷을 야하게 입는다고 도움이 되진 않을꺼 아냐?
Oh my god just please take her.
오 마이 갓, 제발 얘 좀 안아봐
Okay I'll take her, here.
좋아, 내가 안아보지.. 이리와
I have to go to the bathroom.
나 화장실에 가야겠어
I have to go scream into a pillow.
난 베게에다 대고 비명 좀 지르고 와야겠어
통 통 베이비, 통 통 베이비
Bouncy baby, Bouncy baby,
Ooh baby baby, Ooh baby baby,
Ooh baby baby.
오 베이비 베이비, 오 베이비 베이비..
Have I gone deaf?
내가 귀머거리가 된건가?
It worked!
성공이야
Ooh baby baby baby,
ooh baby baby baby!
오 베이비 베이비, 오 베이비 베이비..
You must be a fireball in bed.
넌 침대에서 대단하겠구나
I can't believe it!
She's asleep!
믿기지가 않아, 잠이 들었어
I got her to go to sleep!
내가 재웠다고
I have actual magical powers!
난 진짜 신기한 능력이 있나봐
I can hear traffic and birds!
이제 자동차 소리와 새 지저귀는 소리가 들려
I can hear the voices in my head again!
이제 내 머리속의 목소리도 다시 들리기 시작했어
I'm kidding.
장난이야
Oh my God!
You got her to stop crying!
오 마이 갓! 울음을 멈췄잖아!
Yes I did,
I'm Monica, Super Aunt
그럼, 모니카! 수퍼고모!
You are the official baby crier stopper!
넌 공식적으로 아기 울음 멈추는 사람이야!
Yes I am!!
그렇고 말고
You're never leaving the apartment!
넌 이제 이 아파트를 절대 못 떠나
Say what?
뭐라고?
That's your new job, day and night,
그게 니 새로운 직업이야, 밤낮으로
She starts crying
I need you here.
에마가 울기 시작하면 니가 필요하니까
Oh no no no no!
오 그건 안돼지
Thankfully you don't need me at all
그럼 다행히도 난 아무 필요가 없네
So, Okay.
Super aunt, see you later!
그러니까.. 수퍼고모, 나중에 보자
Rachel! let's give it six to eight months.
레이첼, 6~8개월후에나 보자
Okay, so listen! I'm gonna go lay down.
자 그럼 나 좀 가서 누울께
What?
You know the book says
that whenever she's sleeping
뭐라고?
저 책에 나와있어, 아기가 잘때는 엄마도 꼭 자야한데
I should be sleeping.
So….
그래도 넌.. 와
Hey!
Shhh! We just got her to go to sleep
안녕
방금 잠이 들었어
Oh so there can't be any yelling.
오, 그러면 소리 지르면 안되는거야?
No.
그래
We're moving to Tulsa
우리 툴사로 이사가게 됬어
What!?
Shhhh! Shhhhh! Shhhhh! Shhhhh!
뭐라고?
I can't, I can't hear you.
안들려, 안들린다고
안녕
Hey.
Heeeeey, where have you been?
어디갔다 온거야?
어떻게 된거야?
What happened to you?
조이랑 일이 좀 있었지
Ah I had a little thing with Joey,
이거 보고 놀랄 정도면 조이를 보면 놀라 자빠질껄
If you think this is bad you should see him.
오 안돼, 로스.. 이러면 안돼
Oh no Ross! This is not good,
제발 이 조이 일에 대해서 얘기 좀 해야돼, 앉아봐
We have to talk about this Joey thing.
Please sit.
이 조이에 관한 일은 제발 화를 풀어야해
You have got to get over this Joey thing,
okay?
알겠어? 난 조이랑 진심으로 결혼하고 싶었던게 아니라고
I never really wanted to marry Joey,
okay?
알았어
Okay.
내가 진정으로 원하는게 뭔지 알아?
You know what I really really want?
뭔데, 레이첼?
What, Rach?
잠 좀 자고 싶어
I wanna sleep,
먹고 싶고
I wanna eat,
샤워도 하고 싶어
I wanna take a shower,
에마가 일어나기 전에 말이야,
I mean before she wakes up
또 이 모든걸 다시 해야하니까
and we gotta do this all over again.
그래
진짜 오늘 느낀 건데 말이야,
Right.
I mean I got news for you mister,
에마는... 전혀 쉽지가 않아
Emma? Not easy.
그래, 그게 내가 옆에 있는 이유니까
Well, that's what I'm here for.
내가 가볼까?
괜찮아
Want me to get that?
No its really okay…
모니카?
Monica!
알았어, 가고 있어
Got it! Got it! Got it! Got it! Got it! Got it!
있잖아 생각을 좀 해봤는데, 진짜로 말이지..
[Central Perk]
내 잘못이 아니야, 자연적인 본능이라고
무슨 얘기 하는거야?
You know, ah, I've been thinking about this
and I gotta tell ya,
좋아, 내가 이렇게 하면 어떻게 하겠냐?
It's not my fault.
It's a natural instinct.
Hey, what you guys talking about?
Hey OK great, what would you do if I did this?
피드백을 홈페이지 게시판에 남겨주시면 감사하겠습니다.
South Park Korean Translation Team
E- mail: spkor@hotmail.com
WWW: http://www.spkor.com
End